I want to cover two questions that came up the first of which is around the
strategy of actually tracking the increment amount. So as we can see here
what we're doing right now is using view to track the increment amount using this
vModel directive. So down here we can see inside of this reactive data we have it
tracked in here and the question is why do we even do this? Which is actually a
good question because theoretically if we go ahead and comment this out and we
go up here and we don't even attach any view powers to this particular input
element technically the text element knows what it's doing right it knows
that it has this I chose a smaller number it's fine it knows that it has
123 inside already why are we using view to also check it so in other words
especially before sort of reactive frameworks became really a big thing a
common strategy for this was that every time you wanted to increment
increment the count we would basically go and check the DOM to see what the
source of truth is right and so a completely valid approach and one that
we use for many many years in web development but as websites and
applications have gotten more complex the problem is that if we were to have
some method again call it check input for value that's being run right here
again this is pseudo code just in case anyone's afraid they miss anything
the reason this is ends up becoming a problem is because there ends up being
kind of like an inefficient performance bottleneck in the sense that now every
time someone's running this increment count they're going to check the dumb
regardless of the fact that nothing has actually changed and so that's what a
lot of reactivity system has provided for us from like a developer experience
convenience and also abstracting some of those performance concerns away is
because again for this particular example the performance difference is
probably negligible to be honest to just check an input element real quick if it's
the number pass it back and then run it but we can envision when you have
complex data visualizations when you have a lot of things working with each other if you have to check the
DOM every single time for every single element that has that source of truth
you're going to end up with some conflict and then it'll probably be slower because
once again if those things haven't changed there's no reason to even check that to
begin with so as a result of that this is why and so the more modern frameworks we
have the ability to cache things and have these reactivity tracking and that's
where the advantage of actually making sure that you track that reactive data makes our
lives a lot easier so great question again for that one okay so let's go and
reset this part real quick so we don't ruin the code one two three and then we had
the v model here increment amount let me save that make sure this works this does great okay
in addition there was a second question here in regards to what happens when you
actually want to pass an argument to the method so in this particular case what if
for example an increment count we wanted to pass it our own variable so in this case
let's just say 10 and then for whatever reason again we're spitballing here in
increment count we're gonna check if the argument is greater than the what's inside of
this that increment amount then we'll basically use the argument instead of the
reactive variable again a little bit convoluted but we're kind of going on the fly here so in
increment count I mentioned before that typically when something's being run it's
by default pass an event object so once again to show that this works let me just
go ahead and log event real quick and then remove the argument save refresh console
you can see the pointer event is being registered however if I add that 10 here
and refresh you'll see 10 is being passed and that's because what view does is it
goes okay at this point I don't know how many arguments you're going to pass because you
could pass a bunch of different ones if you wanted to and so rather than try to try like
sort of force you to remember that the event object is there the default event object that's
being passed you basically gets pushed to the end so if we still wanted to access the event
object in this regard we would say for example now this is not actually new this is not actually
event it's new amount and then we also have the event object that's being attached at the end so
once again just to make sure that this actually works as intended so when it comes to how view
handles that default event because it cannot predict where that default event needs to be brought in
you actually pass it in as this basically you explicitly define it so you can see here dollar sign
event that passes the standard javascript event to the function and that way in case you have any sort
of funky things going on it's very very clear what you're looking for the other thing I wanted to show
with this as well in the docs is that I again I'm not a huge fan of inline events but I just want
you to know it is possible you can inline the event directly there and just actually run the thing if
you want but generally speaking I find that it's a lot cleaner to just have the method there because
again HTML is meant to be in my mind to be readable for users and then the logic and all that stuff we
should abstract that away as much as humanly possible because what it does is it lowers the barrier of
entry for those who might want to come and contribute particularly like if you have designers
on your team who are have front-end abilities but might not be that comfortable with javascript
by attracting that stuff away it just makes the code a lot more approachable for them
so the dollar sign event is the answer for that so just to show that inside of the code actually so
that we have cons or I guess consistency here again this is the event but it is not passed by default to do
do we need to go inside of here and we say dollar sign event now when we increment there we go we have a
pointer and we have our account all right question so what's the difference between the at click and the
v on click at click is that's just an html5 attribute right ah okay good question no no no it actually
segues really well so something you'll notice here is that right now we're doing this v on and v bind
where's my v bind oh v bind is gone in this particular case okay that's fine we interact with elements a
lot as far as like interactivity and events so rather than forcing you to type v on all the time
there is a shorthand which is the at symbol and so if you shortcut that that'll basically do exactly
what you expect in terms of the v on but otherwise it's a syntactic sugar to basically say you don't
have to type those one two three four five characters anymore just do at which honestly I think is a
fairly intuitive shortcut when it comes to saying ah yes at click do this thing at key up do this thing
et cetera and so I mentioned v bind and just for the sake of showing that one I'll just do a data
attribute called increment by because sometimes you know you're rendering stuff to the server or some
other app needs something here and let's say you want to render increment amount to this p element and
so if we look at this p element right here you'll notice uh there's the wrong one it is no that should
be oh I didn't refresh that's why boom okay you see that the attribute data increment by is there
available for you but once again we need it to be bound and I said before that you could do v bind
and that will go ahead and change that to actually say ah yes the increment by we're looking at is eight
but again dynamically binding attributes very very common so what can you do instead you can just
delete v bind and just prefix your attribute with the colon another shorthand right or wrong way
there's no right or wrong way most people end up eventually getting used to the convention so you see
that a lot in code bases but otherwise it's up to you on how you want to write your code